chapter 2 of black Beauty this LibriVox recording is in the public
domain Black Beauty by Anna suul chapter 2 The Hunt Before I was 2 years old a
circumstance happened which I have never forgotten. It was early in the spring;
there had been a little frost in the night, and a light mist still hung over
the woods and meadows.
I and the other Cults were feeding at the lower part of the field when we
heard, quite in the distance, what sounded like the cry of
dogs. The oldest of the colts raised his head, pricked his ears, and said, “There are
the hounds!” and immediately caned off, followed by the rest of us to the upper
part of the field, where we could look over the hedge and see several fields
beyond. My mother and an old riding horse of our masters were also was standing
near, and seemed to know all about it. “They have found a hair said my mother,
“and if they come this way we shall see the hunt.” And soon the dogs were all tearing
down the field of young wheat next to our I never heard such a noise as they
made. They did not bark, nor howl, nor
whine, but kept on a “yo Yoo wo yo wo wo yo at the top of their voices.
After them came a number of men on horseback, some of them in green coats,
all galloping as fast as they could. The old horse snorted and looked eagerly
after them, and we young colts wanted to be galloping with them, but they were
soon away into the fields lower down; here it seemed as if they had come to a
stand; the dogs left off barking, and ran about every way with their noses to the
ground. “They have lost the scent,” said said the old horse; “perhaps the hair will get
off.” “What hair I said. “Oh! I don't know what hair likely
enough it may be one of our own hairs out of the woods; any hair they can find
will do for the dogs and men to run after;” and before long the dogs began
their “yo! yo wo wo again, and back they came all together at full speed, making
straight for our meadow at the part where the high bank and hedge overhang the brook.
“Now we shall see the hair said my mother; and just then a hair wild with fright
rushed by and made for the woods. On came the dogs; they burst over
the bank leapt the stream, and came dashing across the field followed by the
huntsmen. Six or eight men leaped their horses clean over, close upon the
dogs. The hair tried to get through the fence; it was too thick, and she turned
sharp round to make for the road, but it was too late; the dogs were upon her with
their wild cries; we heard one shriek, and that was the end of
her. One of the huntsmen rode up and whipped off the dogs, who would soon have
torn her to pieces. He held her up by the leg torn and bleeding, and all the gentlemen
seemed well pleased. As for me, I was so astonished
that I did not at first see what was going on by the brook; but when I did
look there was a sad sight; two fine horses were down, one was
struggling in the stream, and the other was groaning on the
grass. One of the riders was getting out of the water covered with mud, the other lay quite
still. “His neck is broke,” said my mother.
“And serve him right, too,” said one of the colts. I thought the same, but my mother
did not join in with us. “Well, no,” she said, “you must not say
that; but though I am an old horse, and have seen and heard a great deal, I never
yet could make out why men are so fond of this sport; they often hurt themselves,
often spoil good horses, and tear up the
fields, and all for a hair or a fox, or a stag, that they could get more easily
some other way; but we are only horses, and don't know.” While my mother was saying this we
stood and looked on. Many of the riders had gone to the young man; but my master,
who had been watching what was going on, was the first to raise
him. His head fell back and his arms hung down, and everyone looked very
serious. There was no noise now; even the dogs were quiet, and seemed to know that something was
wrong. They carried him to our master's house. I heard afterward that it was
young George Gordon, the squire's only son fine, tall young man, and the pride of his
family. There was now riding off in all directions to the doctors to the farers
and no doubt to Squire Gordons to let him know about his
son. When Mr. Bond, the farer came to look at the black horse that lay groaning on
the grass, he felt him all over, and shook his head; one of his legs was
broken. Then someone ran to our master's house and came back with a gun; presently
there was a loud bang and a dreadful shriek, and then all was still; the black
horse moved no more. My mother seemed much troubled; she
said she had known that horse for years, and that his name was “Rob Roy”; he was a
good horse, and there was no vice in him.
She would never go to that part of the field afterward. Not many days after we heard
the church bell tolling for a long time, and looking over the gate we saw a long,
strange black coach that was covered with black cloth and was drawn by black
horses; after that came another and another and another, and all were black,
while the bell kept tolling, tolling. They were carrying young Gordon
to the churchard to bury him. He would never ride again. What they did with Rob
Roy I never knew; but was all for one little hair
end of chapter